{
    "id": "05b63aebf61d46d6bb0c7920d38bfd99",
    "title": "Simple Past Vs. Present Perfect Tense",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "bc530b2719f04cb69676e3b19bd25782",
            "title": "Simple Past Vs. Present Perfect Tense",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "He ………………………… born in",
                    "description": "Use the simple past to talk about the year in which people were born.",
                    "answers": [
                        "was",
                        "has been",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "She …………………………….. any interest in politics.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "never showed",
                        "has never showed",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ………………………….. all of my friends to my party.",
                    "description": "In British English, the present perfect is common here. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "invited",
                        "have invited",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "None of my friends …………………………. up for my party.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "turned",
                        "has turned",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "My grandmother …………………………… at the age of",
                    "description": "Use the simple past to talk about a completely finished event. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "died",
                        "has died",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "She ………………………… last month after a prolonged battle against cancer.",
                    "description": "You cannot use the present perfect with past time expressions like last month. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "died",
                        "has died",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I …………………………….. up several times in the night.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "woke",
                        "have woken",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I …………………………. to hear the news of his accident.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "was shocked",
                        "have been shocked",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "They ……………………………. in July.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "got married",
                        "have been gotten married",
                        "were gotten"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ………………………… the whole of yesterday in bed.",
                    "description": "We cannot use the present perfect tense with past time expressions.",
                    "answers": [
                        "spent",
                        "have spent",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I …………………………. a lot of places on my last holiday.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "visited",
                        "have visited",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ………………………… them for a long time.",
                    "description": "The present perfect is used to talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "knew",
                        "have known",
                        "was knowing"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}